SHELDON: I must say, Leonard...
Je dois dire, Leonard,
...when I first heard your idea for Giant Jenga l was skeptical.
que j'étais sceptique à l'idée de faire un Jenga géant.
I can't blame you, Tiny Twister was a complete bust.
Je te comprends. Le mini Twister a été un échec.
Oh. But I was wrong.
Mais j'avais tort.
The looming threat of being crushed under a pile of lumber...
La menace imminente d'être écrasé sous une pile de bois
...does add a certain spice.
ajoute un certain piment.
I've never felt so alive.
Je me sens débordant de vie.
Oh, hello, Alex. Let me go get you last night's recordings.
Bonjour, Alex. Je vous donne les enregistrements d‘hier.
What recordings?
Comment ça ?
Remember when you told me I talk in my sleep?
Tu m'as dit que je parlais en dormant.
It occurred to me that like most things I say, it's probably pure gold.
Il est fort probable que ces paroles valent leur pesant d‘or.
So I started recording it all and...
J'ai donc commencé atout enregistrer
...now Alex gets to comb through...
et Alex doit faire le tri
...eight hours of whatl like to call "Sheldon After Dark."
parmi les huit heures de "Sheldon dans le noir".
-Hey, Leonard. -Hey.
- Bonjour.
Just playing a little Giant Jenga.
Nous jouons a Jenga géant.
I know, I'm the one who had to buy him the helmet.
Je sais. C‘est moi qui lui ai acheté le casque.
So do you have plans this weekend?
Des projets pour samedi ?
Most of Saturday's gonna be figuring out where to put this game when we're done.
Je vais passer lajournée a trouver un endroit où ranger ce jeu.
How about you?
Et vous ?
I'm gonna go hear Kip Thorne give a lecture about subatomic space-time.
Je vais a une conférence sur l'espace—temps subatomique.
Oh, that's his take on John Wheeler's quantum foam. That should be great.
Le débat sur la théorie de John Wheeler. C‘est génial !
Well, you can come with me.
Vous devriez venir.
I'd love to, but I'm supposed to hang out with Penny.
J'aimerais bien mais je sors avec Penny.
-Well, bring her. -She's not really into in that kind of stuff.
- Venez avec elle. - Ça ne la branche pas trop.
Well, if you want to hear about the lecture, I can tell you all about it at work...
Si vous voulez un résumé, je peux vous en parler au travail
...or, you know, over dinner sometime.
ou lors d'un dîner.
What?
Quoi ?
Giant Jenga! lwin!
Jenga géant ! J'ai gagné!
Oh, come on, that can't be true.
Non, c‘est impossible.
I did the research. Tony the Tiger...
J'ai fait des recherches. Tony le tigre,
...Dig 'Em the frog, Cap'N Crunch, Toucan Sam, Count Chocula, Trix the Rabbit...
Smacks la grenouille, Cap'N Crunch, Sam le toucan, Trix le lapin,
...Snap, Crackle and Pop.
Cric, Crac et Croc.
Not one cereal mascot is a girl.
Aucune mascotte féminine pour les céréales.
It's a total breakfast sausage fest.
C‘est un rassemblement de testostérones.
Are we done with this?
Ça y est, tu as fini ?
Almost. Franken Berry, Boo Berry, Sugar Bear, and the Honey Nut Cheerio Bee.
Fresque. Franken Berry, Boo Berry, Ours Brun et l‘abeille de Cheerio.
I believe his name is Buzz.
Je crois que son nom est Buzz.
Terrific. Something weird happened and I don't know what to do about it.
Il s‘est passé un truc étrange etj'ignore comment réagir.
-What's going on? -Sheldon's assistant...
- Quoi ? - L'assistante de Sheldon
...asked me on a date.
m‘a invité à sortir.
How could you do that to me?
Comment oses-tu ?
You know I've been working it with Alex for weeks.
Tu sais que j'essaie dela séduire depuis des semaines.
Working it? You can't even talk to her.
La séduire, toi ? Tu ne lui asjamais parlé.
I talk with my eyes.
Je parle avec mes yeux.
You look like my little cousin when he's dropping one in his diaper.
On dirait mon petit cousin quand il fait dans sa couche.
She knows I have a girlfriend. It's so weird.
Elle sait que j'ai une petite amie. C‘est trop bizarre.
Oh, my God. You're loving this!
Et ça te plait !
To my bones.
J‘adore ça !
I'm not gonna do anything about it. I love Penny.
Je ne vais rien faire. J'aime Penny.
It's just nice to have a young, attractive woman sniffing around the goods.
Mais c‘est agréable de se faire désirer par une belle jeune femme.
I both hate you and want to be you. This is Ryan Gosling all over again.
Je te hais etje voudrais être toi. Comme Ryan Gosling.
Aww. Gentlemen. What is on the conversational menu this morning?
Messieurs, quelle conversation est au menu de ce matin ?
Leonard stole my woman, and he knew...
Leonard m‘a volé ma femme
...l was only six to eight months away from making my move.
alors que, dans six mois, je comptais me lancer.
I didn't steal anyone.
Je n'ai volé personne.
Your assistant is totally hitting on this jerk and he loves it.
Ton assistante en bave pour ce crétin et il adore ça.
Well, that's not acceptable. I'm her boss.
Ce n‘est pas acceptable. Je suis son patron.
She needs to be solely focused on my needs...
Elle doit être concentrée sur mes besoins
...not distracted by your pasty, androgynous brand of sexuality.
et non distraite par tes manières sexuelles androgynes.
I'm androgynous?
Je suis androgyne ?
Oh, please. Look at you with your pouty bee-stung lips.
Arrête donc. Regarde tes lèvres en forme de dard.
What do you think I should do?
Qu‘est—ce que je dois faire ?
I say you tell Alex your heart belongs to Penny.
Dis—lui que ton cœur appartient a Penny.
I provide her a shoulder to cry on, then roughly half a year later...
Je serai une épaule réconfortante et, dans six mois,
...I give it to her good.
je lui saute dessus.
I want to thank you all for coming on such short notice. In the past...
Je veux vous remercier d‘être venues si rapidement. Parle passé,
...l've reached out to each of you individually...
je me suis adressé à vous de manière individuelle
...butl believe my present situation requires the collective wisdom of the group.
mais la situation actuelle nécessite toute la sagesse de ce groupe.
Which, as you can see from your commemorative t-shirts, I've dubbed...
Groupe que j'ai appelé, comme vous pouvez le voir sur vos T-shirts,
...Sheldon Cooper's Council of Ladies.
le Conseil des Femmes de Sheldon Cooper.
What is happening?
Que se passe-t-il ?
I need your advice about a delicate workplace situation.
J'ai besoin de conseils sur une situation professionnelle délicate.
To protect those involved, I'll be changing their names.
Pour conserver l‘anonymat, je vais utiliser de faux noms.
Who's involved?
L'anonymat de qui ?
A short, bespectacled colleague of mine...
Un de mes collègues, petit et binoclard,
...who lives in the shadow of his brilliant roommate.
qui vit dans l‘ombre de son brillant colocataire.
-You're talking about Leonard. -No, no.
- Tu parles de Leonard. - Non.
Shilly-Shally has red hair and briefly served in the Mexican Navy.
Girouette est roux
Anyway, despite the fact that he has a girlfriend...
Peu importe. Il a une petite amie
...Shilly-Shally has been the recipient...
et pourtant, Girouette est l‘objet
...of inappropriate workplace flirtations from a young lady.
de flirts inappropriés sur son lieu de travail.
-lt's your assistant Alex, isn't it? -No.
- Tu parles de ton assistante ? - Non.
No, it's Tondelaya della Ventimiglia.
Non. Il s'agit de Tondelaya della Ventimiglia.
What the hell is going on with Leonard and Alex?
Que se passe-t-il entre Leonard et Alex ?
I'm sorry, who's talking about Leonard and Alex?
Je suis désolé. Qui parle de Leonard et Alex ?
Fine. Ricardo and Tondelaya.
D‘accord. Ricardo et Tondelaya.
It's not really about Ricardo and Tondelaya.
Il ne s'agit pas vraiment d'eux.
It is really about her boss...
Mais de son patron a elle
...who doesn't quite know how to handle this situation and could use your advice...
qui ignore comment gérer la situation et qui voudrait des conseils,
...which is surprising, because Dr. Einstein Von Brainstorm...
ce qui est surprenant, car le Dr Einstein Von Brainstorm
...he's usually pretty smart about these things.
est, en temps normal, plutôt doué.
Ugh. I'm gonna kill her!
Je vais la tuer!
You've got nothing to worry about. Leonard would never cheat on you.
Ne crains rien. Il ne te tromperait pour rien au monde.
She's right. But say the word, I got a lab full of cocaine-addicted monkeys...
Elle a raison. Mais tu n'as qu'un mot a dire. Les singes du labo
...with nothing to lose.
n‘ont rien a perdre.
One of them could end up in the back seat of her car.
L'un d‘eux pourrait se faufiler dans sa voiture.
Or her shower.
Ou dans sa douche.
Ladies, ladies, please. We're not here to talk about Penny.
Mesdames. Nous ne parlons pas de Penny.
We're here to talk about me. I mean Einstein Von Brainstorm! Darn it.
Nous parlons de moi. Enfin, d'Einstein Von Brainstorm ! Mince.
All right, I guess the cat's out of the bag.
D‘accord. J'ai vendu la mèche.
Let me explain what's going on. Ricardo is really Leon--
Laissez—moi vous expliquer. Ricardo est Leonard.
We know what's going on, Sheldon!
On a compris, Sheldon !
But what should I do?
Je fais quoi moi maintenant ?
Alex is your employee. If she's doing something that's...
Alex est ton employée. Si son attitude met
...making Leonard uncomfortable, you should talk to her.
Leonard mal a l‘aise, tu dois lui parler.
Oh, he's not uncomfortable at all. He's loving it.
Il n‘est pas mal a l‘aise. Il adore ça.
He's strutting around like he's 5-foot-6.
Il se pavane comme s'il mesurait 1,70 m.
What? He's loving it?
Quoi ? Il adore ça ?
Sheldon, you need to talk to Alex right away.
Sheldon, tu dois parler à Alex tout de suite.
Talk to her. That's all you've got?
C‘est tout ce que vous proposez ?
With a cool name like Sheldon Cooper's Council of Ladies...
De la part du Conseil des Femmes de Sheldon Cooper,
...I really expected more.
je m‘attendais à mieux.
Give me back the t-shirts.
Rendez—moi vos T-shirts.
Alex, check my schedule. What does my afternoon look like?
Alex, regardez mon planning. J'ai quelque chose de prévu ?
I think it's pretty wide open. Oh, wait. Here's something at 4:00.
Je ne crois pas. Oh, attendez. Un rendez-vous à 16 h.
"Give Alex a talking to"?
"Discussion avec Alex" ?
Well, that snuck up on us, didn't it?
Un rendez-vous surprise, on dirait!
-Is there a problem? -Let's not call it a problem...
- Un problème ? - Ce n‘est pas un probléme
...let's call it an opportunity.
mais plutôt une opportunité.
To solve a serious problem.
Pour résoudre un problème.
What did I do?
Qu'ai-je fait ?
You don't know? Oh, you poor dear.
Vous l‘ignorez ? Ma pauvre.
Your ovaries are squirting so much goofyjuice into your brain...
Vos ovaires ont pris le dessus sur votre cerveau
...you don't know which way is up.
et vous ignorez ce que vous faites.
You made an inappropriate sexual advance towards Dr. Hofstadter.
Vous avez fait des avances sexuelles inappropriées au Dr Hofstadter.
What? I didn't make a sexual advance on anybody.
Quoi ? Je n'ai fait d‘avances sexuelles a personne.
Now, there's no need to get defensive.
Ne soyez pas sur la défensive.
I'm not unsympathetic to your plight.
Je comprends votre détresse.
My father used to say that a woman is like...
Mon père m‘a toujours dit que les femmes sont
...an egg salad sandwich on a warm Texas day.
comme un sandwich œufs-salade lors d‘une chaude journée au Texas.
What?
Pardon ?
Full of eggs and only appealing for a short time.
Plein d'œufs mais attirant que l'espace d'un court instant.
This conversation is making me uncomfortable.
Cette discussion me met mal a l‘aise.
Yeah, you and me both, sister.
Et moi donc !
Please understand, I don't hold you responsible for your behavior.
Sachez que je ne vous tiens pas pour responsable de votre attitude.
From an evolutionary standpoint, you're a slave to your desire to reproduce.
En fait, vous êtes l‘esclave de votre désir de vous reproduire.
But during the work day...
Mais dans lajournée,
...when you feel possessed by amorous intent, may I suggest...
quand vous vous sentez prise d'un élan amoureux, je vous suggère
...you suppress it by leafing through this illustrated book...
d‘y mettre fin en feuilletant ce livre illustré
...of sexually transmitted diseases.
sur les maladies sexuelles.
Oh, yes. Check out this oozy doozy.
Oui. Regardez ce bouton suintant.
l have to go.
Je dois partir.
So does this fellow, but he can't without it burning like hot soup.
Comme ce type. Mais ça doit le brûler.
Hey, pretty lady.
Salut, beauté.
You seem extra happy.
Tu as l‘air super heureux.
-I guess I am. -Any particular reason why?
- Je le suis. - Pour quelle raison ?
No, just having a good day.
Je passe une bonnejournée.
This morning Sheldon fell asleep on the way to work...
Ce matin, Sheldon s‘est endormi en voiture
...so I got to listen to the radio. That was crazy.
etj'ai pu écouter la radio. C‘était super.
Mm-hm. Anything else?
Autre chose ?
Mm.... I found this quiz online called "Which Star Trek Character Are You?"
J'ai découvert un test en ligne sur les personnages de Star Trek,
It only took me four tries to get Captain Kirk. Heh.
que j'ai dû faire 4 fois pour tomber sur Capitaine Kirk.
-That's great. -Oh.
- Génial. - Oh. Ça. L'est.
And the one thing that could make it better is an evening with my special girl.
Et, pour couronner le tout, je passe la soirée avec ma copine géniale.
Oh, and who's that?
Et qui est-ce ?
What do you mean?
Pardon ?
I just didn't know if you meant me or Alex.
Tu parles de moi ou d'Alex ?
Why would I mean Alex?
Pourquoi Alex ?
Because I know she hit on you and I know you liked it!
Elle te court après et tu adores ça !
[NERVOUSLY] What?
Quoi ?
Don't play dumb with me, Ricardo Shilly-Shally!
Ne me prends pas pour une idiote, Ricardo Girouette.
I'm missing something.
J'ai dû rater un épisode.
Did you say something to Penny about Alex?
Tu as parlé d'Alex a Penny ?
Yes, and a fat lot of good it did me. All she did was get mad at you.
Oui, et ça ne m‘a servi à rien. Elle est furieuse après toi.
Why would you do that?
Pourquoi as-tu fait ça ?
I needed advice about a woman.
J‘avais besoin de conseils.
I would have asked you, but if the last few years have proven anything...
J'aurais pu te demander mais ces dernières années ont prouvé
...it's that you can't tell a uterus from a unicycle.
que tu ne sais pas comment fonctionne un utérus.
At least I know not to blab to a girl about somebody flirting with her boyfriend.
Mais je sais qu'il ne faut pas parler d'un flirt a une fille.
...you may find yourself on the Council of Ladies.
et tu feras partie de mon Conseil de Femmes.
Hello?
Allô ?
I see. What time?
Je vois. A quelle heure ?
Very well, then.
Trés bien.
Apparently my assistant, Alex, has filed a complaint accusing me of...
Apparemment, mon assistante, Alex, m'accuse
...inappropriate behavior in the workplace.
d‘avoir un comportement inapproprié.
Oh, my God. What did you do?
Oh, mon Dieu. Qu‘est—ce que tu as fait ?
Oh. Let me think....
Laisse—moi réﬂéchir…
Nothing, I'm a delight.
Rien. Je suis un ange.
Human Resources Department.
Ressources humaines.
Come in?
Entrez ?
-Hello. -Ah. Dr. Cooper, have a seat.
- Bonjour. - Dr Cooper, asseyez-vous.
Thank you.
Merci.
I called you in today because your assistant...
Je vous ai appelé car votre assistante,
...Alex Jensen has lodged a complaint against you.
Alex Jensen, a déposé une plainte.
So I've been told. But I can't understand what she has to complain about.
On me l‘a dit. Mais je ne vois pas de quoi elle peut se plaindre.
She has a front row seat as I make scientific history...
Elle est au premier rang pour assister a mes prouesses.
...there's string cheese in my mini-fridge and that's for anyone...
Il y a du fromage dans le frigo et elle peut se servir.
...and just yesterday I led her away from a life of sexual promiscuity...
Et hier, je lui ai évité une vie de promiscuité sexuelle
...by making her look at pictures of disease-ridden genitalia.
en lui montrant des images de maladies sur les organes génitaux.
Cancel my next appointment. This is gonna take a while.
Annulez mon prochain rendez—vous. La séance va être longue.
Dr. Cooper, you said things to your employee...
Vous avez dit des choses a votre employée
...that you just cannot say in the workplace.
qui ne se disent pas au bureau.
Like what?
Comme quoi ?
Well, according to Ms. Jensen you said...
Vous avez dit qu'elle était
...that she was a "slave to her biological urges"...
"l'esclave de ses besoins" et qu'elle était ”un sandwich aux œufs".
I don't even know what that means...
J'ignore ce que ça signifie
...but I'm gonna go ahead and tell you you can't say it.
mais vous ne pouvez pas dire ce genre de choses.
Oh, I see the confusion here.
Oh, je vois d'où Vient le malentendu.
Alex thought I was singling her out. No.
Alex pense que je parlais d'elle en particulier. Non.
I meant that all women are slaves to their biological urges.
Toutes les femmes sont esclaves de leurs besoins biologiques.
Even you.
Même vous.
You're a slave.
Vous êtes une esclave.
I'm a what?
Pardon ?
I'm just saying. At a certain point in a woman's menstrual cycle--
A un moment donné du cycle menstruel de la femme...
You can't talk about that either.
Vous ne pouvez pas parler de ça.
Your language is entirely inappropriate, and I'm going to advise...
Ce que vous dites est inapproprié etje vous conseille
...that you shut your mouth right now.
dela boucler maintenant.
I don't see why I'm the one being persecuted here.
J'ai l'impression d‘être persécuté.
Dr. Hofstadter was bragging about his sexual desirability...
Dr Hofstadter parle de ses conquêtes sexuelles
...to anyone who would listen.
a qui veut l‘entendre.
Howard Wolowitz spent two years using university resources...
Howard Wolowitz utilise le matériel de l'université
...building a six-breasted sex robot.
pour construire un robot sexuel.
And at the office Christmas party, I heard Rajesh Koothrappali...
Lors dela fête de Noël du bureau, j'ai entendu Rajesh Koothrappali
...refer to you several times as "Brown Sugar."
parler de vous comme du "Sucre Brun".
Hofstadter, Wolowitz and that last one was Rajesh Koothrappali?
Hofstadter, Wolowitz et Rajesh Koothrappali ?
Yes. But in his defense, that wasn't racist. He's also brown.
Mais il ne tenait aucun propos raciste.
[SINGING] I'm sorry Alex hi! on me
Désolé qu‘Alex me drague
Hi! on me, hit on me
Me drague, me drague
Sorry Alex hi! on me [had no idea I'm cute
J‘ignorais que j‘étais mignon
Aw. Damn it, you are.
C‘est vrai, tu l‘es.
Please forgive me, I should have told you about Alex.
Pardonne-moi, je t'en prie. J'aurais du te parler d‘Alex.
I don't care about Alex. Fine, I care.
Je me moque d‘elle. En fait, non.
Okay, I hate the bitch.
Je déteste cette garce.
But what really hurt is that you liked it so much.
Le plus dur, c‘est que ça te plaise.
Do I need to be worried?
Je dois m‘inquiéter ?
Of course not. No. Why?
Bien sûr que non. Pourquoi ?
Because she's pretty and smart and when you talk about work...
Elie estjolie, intelligente et, quand tu parles,
...she doesn't have to look up words in the dictionary...
elle n‘a pas besoin d'un dictionnaire
...to understand what you said.
pour te comprendre.
-You do that? -No.
- Tu fais ça ? - Non.
Hang on. Are you feeling insecure? Because that's my thing.
Tu manques de confiance en toi ? C‘est mon rôle d‘habitude.
And if you take it away, I don't know what I'm bringing to this relationship.
Si c‘est bien le cas, je ne sais pas comment gérer ça.
Yes, Leonard, I am insecure. Happy?
Oui, Leonard, je manque de confiance en moi. Content ?
No, I'm not happy.
Non. Loin delà.
Why are you smiling?
Pourquoi tu souris ?
I'm sorry, it's just I never think of you having feelings like that.
J'ignorais que ça pouvait t'arriver.
-Well, I do. -Why?
- Ben si. - Pourquoi ?
Nothing is ever going to happen between me and Alex.
Rien ne se passera entre moi et Alex.
Come here.
Viens la.
-Can I tell you a secret? -What's that?
- Je peux te dire un secret ? -Oui.
With all these women chasing me, I kind of do feel like Captain Kirk.
Avec toutes ces femmes, je me sens comme le Capitaine Kirk.
-Can I tell you a secret? -Sure.
- Je peux te dire un secret ? -Oui.
Keep talking about Captain Kirk and we're all gonna stop.
Continue a parler de lui et tu peux dire adieu aux femmes.
[MIMICS CAPTAIN KIRK] Message. Received.
Message reçu.
Excuse me.
Excuse-moi.
Hello.
Allô.
This is Dr. Hofstadter.
Ici Dr Hofstadter.
Okay.
D‘accord.
All right, thank you.
Trés bien. Merci.
That's weird. I'm getting called into Human Resources.
Bizarre. C‘était les ressources humaines.
What did you do?
Qu'as-tu fait ?
I don't know.
Je ne sais pas.
Why?
Pourquoi ?
I don't know. Heh.
Aucune idée.
Could you stop licking your ass for two minutes? I have a problem here.
Arrête de te lécher le derrière. J'ai des problèmes.
Do you really think you should be drinking right now?
Tu crois vraiment que c‘est le moment ?
How else am I supposed to talk to the human resources lady?
Comment faire pour parler àla femme des ressources humaines ?
I don't know, seek professional help?
Tu devrais voir un professionnel.
I did. The guy at the liquor store said this stuff tastes great in coffee.
C‘est fait. Il a dit que ça se mariait bien avec le café.
You got called in too? What is going on?
Ils t‘ont aussi appelé ? Que se passe-t-il ?
Sheldon threw us all under the bus.
Sheldon nous a dénoncés.
I feel like I've been called to the principal's office.
J'ai l'impression d'attendre le proviseur.
Although I wouldn't mind if Brown Sugar suspended me...
Sauf si Sucre Brun me punit
...from a sex swing. Heh.
à coups de fouet et de cuir.
This may have been a mistake.
J'aurais peut-être pas dû en mettre.
Relax, everything's gonna be fine.
On se calme. Tout va bien.
Before I met Bernadette, l was in here every other day.
Avant de rencontrer Bernadette, je venais souvent ici.
Little tip, turn off your "I Like Big Butts" ringtone before you go in.
Surtout éteint ta sonnerie "J'aime les grosses fesses" avant d‘entrer.
-This is all your fault. -How is this my fault?
- Tout ça est de ta faute. - Ma faute ?
If you weren't screwing around with Sheldon's assistant...
Sans ton histoire avec Alex,
-...this wouldn't have happened. -I wasn't screwing around.
- on n'en serait pas la. - Je n'ai rien fait.
Oh, of course not, she was just sniffing around your goods...
C‘est ça. Elle te tournait autour
...because she was hunting for truffles.
juste pour trouver des truffes.
Hey, Janine. Heh. How're Tom and the kids?
Bonjour, Janine. Comment vont Tom et les enfants ?
You must be Dr. Hofstadter?
Dr Hofstadter ?
Yes, but I thinkthis is all a big misunderstanding.
Oui. Je pense que ceci est un malentendu.
Yeah, me too. I didn't do anything.
Oui, moi aussi. Je n'ai rien fait.
Is that alcohol on your breath?
Vous avez bu ?
Howard built a sex robot.
Howard a construit un robot sexuel.
That is not true. All I did was build a robot.
C‘est faux. J'ai juste construit un robot.
Did it have six breasts?
Avec six seins ?
I'm sorry, I'm a feminist. Heh. I don't notice things like...
Désolé. Je suis un féministe. Je ne remarque pas
...how many breasts a robot has.
le nombre de seins d'un robot.
Well, hello.
Bonjour.
What are you doing here?
Que fais-tu la ?
-Actually, I came to speak to Mrs. Davis. -And I'm a little busy right now.
- Je suis venu voir Mme Davis. - Je suis occupée.
But I came to file a complaint. Somebody has made me feel uncomfortable...
Je Viens porter plainte. Quelqu'un m‘a mis mal a l'aise
...in the workplace by using language of an inappropriate and sexual nature.
sur mon lieu de travail en tenant des propos de nature sexuelle.
-And who is that? -You, you dirty birdy.
- Qui ? - Vous, petite coquine.
I thought about the things you said yesterday...
J'ai repensé a ce que vous m'avez dit
...and I realized I'm deeply offended.
et ça m‘a offensé.
Now, be a dear and get me one of those complaint forms.
Passez—moi un formulaire de plainte.
That's it. All of you, in my office now.
D‘accord. Tous dans mon bureau. Maintenant.
Thanks to you, I know better than to ask if you're menstruating.
Inutile de vous demander si vous avez vos règles.
Based on your behavior, I don't have to.
D‘après votre attitude, c‘est évident.
It has been pointed out to me that some of the things I said to you...
On m‘a signalé que certaines remarques que je vous ai faites
...could be construed as offensive.
pouvaient être considérées comme offensantes.
And I would like to offer you my sincerest apology.
Etje vous présente mes plus sincères excuses.
Thank you, Dr. Cooper.
Merci, Dr Cooper.
Additionally, you should know that the university has mandated...
Sachez que l'université m'oblige
...that I take an online sexual harassment seminar so that this sort of thing...
a suivre un séminaire en ligne sur le harcèlement sexuel
...doesn't happen in the future.
pour que cela n'arrive plus.
-Okay. -Now, unfortunately...
- Bien. - Malheureusement,
...my time is much too valuable to waste on nonsense like this...
mon temps est trop précieux
...so I'm going to need you to take it for me.
donc vous allez le suivre à ma place.
Oh, and you'd better ace it, they're pretty mad.
Faites en sorte de réussir. Ils sont furieux.
-l was thinking about that stuff with Alex-- -Would you stop worrying about that?
- J'ai repensé à Alex... - Arrête de t'inquièter.
I can't help it. But I figured I could sit around...
Je ne peux pas. Soitje reste la, à manquer
...and feel insecure, or I could do something about it.
de confiance, soitje prends les choses en main.
So, I got a course catalog at school and looked at some of the science classes.
J'ai feuilleté un catalogue sur différents cours de science.
-That's great. -No, it isn't...
- Génial. - Non.
...they are extremely boring, how do you not kill yourself, like, every day?
C‘est terriblement ennuyeux. Tu n'as jamais envie de te pendre ?
Anyway, I decided I don't need to be a scientist, I could just look like one.
J'ai décidé de seulement ressembler à une scientifique.
So I bought these.
J'ai acheté ceci.
Glasses? I really don't think that's gonna change--
Des lunettes.
Oh, my God, you look so smart and hot!
Oh mon Dieu ! Tu as l‘air super intelligente et sexy!
I know, right? Watch this.
Je sais. Regarde.
Molecules.
Molécules.
-Okay, come with me. -Where are we going?
- Viens avec moi. - Où ?
To my bedroom so I can take everything off but those glasses.
Dans ma chambre.
And maybe the boots.
Et peut—être les chaussures.
[English - us - an]
[French]